time.graphics 2019-06-08

# Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

TimeGraphics takes the private nature of your personal information very seriously. This Privacy Policy (which we adapted from a policy originally provided by Automattic (WordPress.com)) describes how we treat the information we collect when you visit and use the website available at time.graphics (the “Website”) and is made available under the Creative Commons Sharealike license. Please read this notice carefully.

 **Website Visitors**

Like most website operators, TimeGraphics collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. TimeGraphics’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how TimeGraphics’s visitors use its Website. From time to time, TimeGraphics may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its Website. 

TimeGraphics also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. TimeGraphics does not use such information to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below. 

**Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information**

Certain visitors to the Website choose to interact with TimeGraphics in ways that require TimeGraphics to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that TimeGraphics gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for an account at time.graphics to provide a username and email address. TimeGraphics collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with TimeGraphics. TimeGraphics does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. Visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities. TimeGraphics does not collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If you believe that a child has provided TimeGraphics with personally identifiable information without the consent of his or her parent or guardian, please contact us at support@time.graphics. If TimeGraphics becomes aware that a child under age 13 has provided us with personally identifiable information, we will delete such information. 

**Aggregated Statistics**

TimeGraphics may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to the Website. For instance, TimeGraphics may monitor the most popular public timelines on the time.graphics site to help identify spam. TimeGraphics may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, TimeGraphics does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. 

**Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**

TimeGraphics discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on TimeGraphics’s behalf or to provide services available at the Website, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using the Website, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. In addition, in some cases we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Moreover, if TimeGraphics or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that TimeGraphics goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of TimeGraphics may continue to use your personal and non-personal information only as set forth in this policy. Otherwise, TimeGraphics will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations or as described above, TimeGraphics discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when TimeGraphics believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of TimeGraphics, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of the TimeGraphics Website and have supplied your email address, TimeGraphics may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with TimeGraphics and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. TimeGraphics takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information. For users outside the United States or Germany, please note that any personally-identifiable information you enter into the Website will be transferred out of your country and into the United States or Germany. You consent to such transfer through your use of the Website. You also warrant that you have the right to transfer such information outside your country and into the United States or Germany. 

**Types of Timelines**

TimeGraphics enables you specify the privacy settings on the timelines you create. Timelines can be public (visible to anyone), private (visible only to you), or link-protected (visible to people with a link identificator). 

**Links to Third Party Sites**

This Privacy Policy only applies to information collected by TimeGraphics. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that TimeGraphics does not own or control, or employees that TimeGraphics does not manage. The Website contains links to third party websites. Any information you provide to, or that is collected by, third-party sites may be subject to the privacy policies of those sites, if any. We encourage you to read such privacy policies of any third-party sites you visit. It is the sole responsibility of such third parties to adhere to any applicable restrictions on the disclosure of your personally-identifying information, and TimeGraphics and its affiliates shall not be liable for wrongful use or disclosure of your personally-identifying information by any third party. 

**Security**

All non-personally-identifying information, potentially personally-identifying and personally identifying-information described above is stored on restricted database servers. 

**Cookies**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. TimeGraphics uses cookies to help TimeGraphics identify and track visitors, their usage of the TimeGraphics Website, and their Website access preferences. TimeGraphics visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using the TimeGraphics Website, with the drawback that certain features of TimeGraphics’s Website may not function properly without the aid of cookies. 

**Removing Data**

If you would like to delete the timeline you may do so by clicking the name of your timeline within the editor then clicking the "delete" link, which will purge all existing content from our database. Because we regularly back up our systems, residual copies of your profile information and other information associated with your account may remain on back-up media. 

**Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, TimeGraphics may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in TimeGraphics’s sole discretion. If we do then we’ll notify you by posting the amended policy on the Website or by emailing you of the nature of the modifications along with a link to the modified document so that you can review it. In all cases, use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is collected. 

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this policy or our site in general, please contact us at support@time.graphics
